Tams-Witmark Collection
Music Division, Library of Congress
- Music (Box 1-829)
  - Wallace, (William) Vincent, 1812-1865
    - Desert flower, Manuscript full score; 3 vols. (Box 713-714)
    - Lurine, Manuscript full score; 3 vols. (Box 715-716)
    - Lurine, Manuscript full score; 3 vols. (Box OV-717-718)
    - Maritana, Manuscript full score (Box 719)
    - Maritana, Manuscript parts (Box 720)
    - Maritana*, Manuscript full score (condensed) (Box 720)
  - Waller, Henry
    - The Ogalallas, Manuscript parts (Box 720A-723)
  - Weber, Carl Maria von, 1786-1826
    - Euryanthe. Berlin: Schlesinger, 1866, Manuscript full score; Plate no. S. 4791.; (2 copies). (Box 724)
    - Euryanthe, Manuscript full score (Box 725)
    - Der Freischutz. Leipzig: C. F. Peters, n.d., Printed full score; Plate no. 5373 (6246). (Box 726)
    - Der Freischütz. Berlin: Schlesinger, n.d., Printed full score; Plate no. S. 3512. (Box OV-727)
    - Freischutz, Manuscript full score; 3 vols. (Box 728)
    - Der Freischütz. Leipzig: C. F. Peters, n.d., Printed full score; Plate no. 5373 (6246). (Box 729)
    - Oberon, Manuscript full score; 3 vols. (Box 730)
    - Oberon, Manuscript full score; 3 vols. (Box 731)
    - Preciosa. Berlin: Schlesinger, n.d., Printed full score; Plate no. S. 2913 A. (Box 732)
    - Preciosa. Berlin: Schlesinger, n.d., Printed parts; Plate nos. S. 1093, 20107, S. 3768. (Box 733)
    - Preciosa. Berlin: Schlesinger, 1878, Printed score; Plate no. S. 1093.; (2 copies). (Box 733)
    - Preciosa. Wolfenbüttel: L. Holle, n.d., Printed piano-vocal score; Plate no. (392). (Box 733)
    - Silvana, Printed score (lithograph); 3 vols. (Box 734)
  - Weber, Edw(ard) A.
    - [Lolo-Lied]
      - Lolo-Lulu [Lied], Printed piano-vocal score; manuscript cello part (Box 826)
  - Weil, Oscar, 1839?-1921
    - Pygmalion & Galatea, Manuscript parts (Box 737)
    - Pyramus & Thisbe, Manuscript parts (Box 738)
    - Suzette, Manuscript full score; overture only (Box 739)
    - Suzette, Manuscript parts (Box 739-740)
    - A Wartime wedding/In Mexico, Manuscript full score; 2 vols. (Box 741)
    - In Mexico/ Wartime wedding, Manuscript parts (Box 742-743)
    - Wartime wedding, Manuscript parts (Box 744)
  - Weingartner, (Paul) Felix (1863-1942)
    - House of dreams. Leipzig: Breitkopf & Härtel, 1904/5, Printed full score; Plate no. Part B. 1848. (Box 745)
  - Wetterhahn, Joh. Wilhelm, 1814-1879
    - Quartier für Lebenzeit*, Manuscript parts (Box 745)
    - Quartier für Lebenzeit, Manuscript full score (Box 746)
  - Winter, Peter von, 1754-1825
    - Das Unterbrochene Opferfest/Interrupted feast of thanks, Manuscript parts (Box 746-747)
    - Das Unterbrochene Opferfest, Manuscript full score; [Fragile]. (Box 748)
  - Witmark, Isidore, 1871-1941
    - The Chaperones, Manuscript full score (Box 749)
  - Wolf, Max, 1840-1886
    - Cesarine, Printed full score (lithograph) (Box 750)
    - Die Porträtdame, Printed full score (lithograph) (Box 751)
    - Rafaela, Printed full score (lithograph) (Box 752)
  - Wolff, Wilh[elm]
    - [Das Versprechen hinterm Herd]
      - Der Freiherrals Wildschütz. Leipzig: Philip Reclam Jun., n.d., Printed piano-vocal score (Box 826)
      - Der Freiherrals Wildschütz. Mühlhausen: G. Danner, n.d., Printed piano-vocal score; Plate no. 162. (Box 826)
      - Der Freiherrals Wildschütz, Manuscript and printed parts (Box 826)
      - Der Freiherrals Wildschütz, Printed libretto (Box 826)
  - Zajc, Ivan, 1832-1914
    - Mannschaft an Bord, Manuscript full score (Box 753)
    - Mannschaft am Bord, Manuscript full score (Box 754)
    - Mannschaft an Bord, Manuscript parts (Box 755-756)
  - Zech, J.
    - Die Fränkische Braut. Hamburg: Aug. Fr. Cranz, n.d., Printed full score; Plate no. 332. (Box 756)
  - Zeller, Carl, 1842-1898
    - Der Obersteiger, Printed piano-vocal score; mimeographed soprano and alto parts (Box 826)
    - Der Obersteiger, Manuscript libretto; (3 copies). (Box 826)
    - Der Vagabund, Printed full score (lithograph); Manuscript plot synopsis. (Box 757)
    - Der Vagabund*, Printed full score (lithograph) (Box 758)
    - Der Vagabund, Manuscript parts (Box 759)
  - Ziehrer, C(arl) M(ichael), 1843-1922
    - Schloss Malakulci, Printed full score (lithograph); (2 copies). (Box 760)
  - Zimmer, Carl
    - [Feinsliebchen]
      - An der Havel. Berlin: Hansa Verlag, n.d., Printed piano-vocal score; Plate no. H. V. 299. (Box 826)
  - Various Composers
    - The Girl from Dixie, Manuscript full score; parts (lithograph); Manuscript letter from H. B. S. [Harry B. Smith]. (Box 780)
    - National anthem: France. La Marseillaise, Manuscript full score; parts) (Box 769)
    - National anthem: Portugal. A portuguêsa, Manuscript parts (Box 769)
    - National anthem: Russia. Bozhe, tsara khrani, Manuscript parts (Box 769)
    - National anthem: United States. Star spangled banner, Manuscript parts; Arranged by William Bradbury. (Box 769)
    - Vocal melodies of Scotland. Edinburgh: Paterson & Roy, n.d., Printed piano-vocal score; manuscript parts; Edited by Finley Dun and John Thomson. (Box 154)
    - Miscellaneous sheet music, Printed piano-vocal scores (various publishers); Bound into one volume. (Box 776)
    - Miscellaneous songs, Manuscript piano-vocal scores (Box 787)
  - Anonymous Works
    - Brüderlein Sein, Manuscript parts (violin and cello parts only) (Box 827)
    - Brüderlein Sein, Manuscript libretto (Box 827)
    - Bummel-Marsch, Manuscript parts (Box 827)
    - Confusius, Manuscript full score; Act III only (Box 770)
    - Drei Paar Schuhe, Manuscript piano-vocal score; manuscript parts (Box 827)
    - Ehrliche Arbeit, Manuscript parts (Box 827)
    - Er und Seine Schwester, Manuscript score (piano); [Fragile]. (Box 827)
    - Er und Seine Schwester, Manuscript parts (voice); Additional material laid in. (Box 827)
    - Die Flüchtlinge, Manuscript full score (overture missing) (Box 771)
    - Hotel Klingebusch, Manuscript piano-vocal score (Box 827)
    - Hotel Klingebusch, Manuscript parts (Box 827)
    - Ich hab' mein herz in Heidelberg verloren, Manuscript libretto (Box 827)
    - Judith (Yavith), Manuscript full score; string parts; 1st Tableau only.; Attributed to G. F. Handel. (Box 206)
    - Künstler Traum, Manuscript piano-vocal scores (complete/incomplete sketches); manuscript parts (Box 828)
    - Little boy blue, Manuscript parts; Numbers cut from production. (Box 783)
    - Mädl ohn Geld, Manuscript vocal part (Box 828)
    - Mein Leopold, Manuscript parts; manuscript synopsis (Box 828)
    - Musik für Laienspiele. Potsdam: Ludwig Voggenreiter Verlag, n.d., Printed songbook; Plate no. V. V. 54. (Box 828)
    - Muttersegen, Manuscript parts (Box 828)
    - Rose Marie, Manuscript parts (Box 774)
    - Schnüpflied, Manuscript full score; Includes miscellaneous sketches.; [Fragile]. (Box 775)
    - Unter Geschäftsaufsight, Manuscript parts (Box 828)
    - [Untitled], Manuscript full score (Box 778)
    - [Untitled], Printed full score (lithograph); [Fragile]. (Box 779)
    - Der Vogelhändler, Typed libretto (Box 828)
    - Von Stufe zu Stufe, Manuscript parts (Box 828)
    - Willy's Frau, Typed libretto (Box 828)
  - Miscellaneous Fragments
    - Miscellaneous fragments, Manuscript full score; manuscript piano-vocal score; manuscript parts (Box 454)
    - [Miscellaneous fragments]. Always believe in you, Manuscript full score (Box 788)
    - [Miscellaneous fragments]. Sweetheart like mine, Manuscript score; parts (Box 788)
    - [Miscellaneous fragments]. Let me alone (If you had a sweetheart like mine), Manuscript parts (Box 788)
    - [Miscellaneous fragments]. Anything you say, Manuscript score; manuscript piano-vocal score; manuscript parts (Box 788)
    - [Miscellaneous fragments]. Love me with your lips, Manuscript score (Box 788)
    - [Miscellaneous fragments]. We hate to go when it rains, Manuscript score; manuscript parts (Box 788)
    - Miscellaneous fragments (Box 828)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Cataloguing information on other libraries' Tams-Witmark holdings: University of Wisconsin-Madison (Mills Music Library); Westminster Choir College; The Eastman School of Music (Sibley Music Library); Princeton University (Department of Rare Books and Special Collections) (Box 791)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 828)
    - Assorted works by Hermann Marcellus (Box 829)